Hello world. Did you know that according
to the World Egg Organization? Yes,
that's its actual name, Japan is the
number two per capita consumer of eggs
in the world, right behind Mexico. Well,
before making this video, I didn't
either, but it kind of makes sense when
you consider all of the delicious
varieties of egg dishes in Japan. I'm a
particular fan of the Ajitama in ramen.
However, there's one Japanese dish that
I think you'll find exceptionally
[music]
interesting, and that is tamago kakeake
gohan or tkg for short. It literally
means eggs on rice. Tamago kake Gohan. I
have lived in Japan long enough now that
the idea of eating raw eggs on rice
seems completely normal. You may have
seen me eat raw eggs with sukiyaki in
our coobe beef video, but I recently
realized that eating raw eggs in such an
unadulterated manner really is uncommon
outside of Japan.
So, I wanted to do a bit of a deep dive
and find out the history and knowhow of
this simple yet popular Japanese dish. I
assumed that one of the reasons for the
popularity is that the safety of eggs in
Japan is high. And so we visited a
chicken farm and a couple of TKG eeries,
interviewed a food safety expert, and
heard from some of our viewers from
around the world to get a clearer
picture of the cultural and scientific
facts you might want to consider when
consuming TKG. Like, is it actually safe
to eat raw eggs? Does it matter if
you're in Japan or not? And why do
Japanese people seem to eat raw eggs
more than in other countries? So, with
all that said, let's crack open our
first mystery of where did TKG come
from?
I interrupt this broadcast to [music]
bring you some late breaking news. We've
just finished renovating this
60-year-old home in Niko, and it's
actually where I'm doing all the
narration from. So, if you'd like to
stay in a traditional Japanese home in a
quiet neighborhood, then click or I
guess not click, but scan the QR code on
screen or you can visit
silverdaestay.com
or you can check out the link in the
description. Okay, back [music] to our
regular broadcast. The history of TKG,
at least in any written form, dates back
to the Maji period, roughly between the
years of 1860 and 1890. During that
time, there was a renowned scholar and
pioneer named Ginko Kashida, who
apparently traveled across Japan eating
TKG for breakfast wherever he went.
Whether Ginko Kashida actually
popularized TKG is up for debate, but he
was a successful, well-connected
journalist, so I'm sure that his
peculiar culinary habits caught the
attention of the other influential
people and passers by. These days, TKG
is such a common quick meal, you'd
struggle to find a Japanese person who's
never had it before. But despite being
one of the simplest meals in Japan, you
could literally buy all the necessary
ingredients at a convenience store.
There are actually entire businesses
that build their menus off of TKG. That
means people will go out of their way to
eat this simple dish outside of their
home. One such establishment is Yurin
An, a TKG itery in Kurashiki's famous
Bikan area that attracts both Japanese
and international customers alike. So, I
had Bobby, our producer, and his friend
Rosie check out their shop and meet
their staff.
for
Okay.
Feel like I put too much soy sauce.
Really good.
Cuz I think after you mix the yolk and
the soy sauce, it's not very like slimy.
You can't really tell. [music] At least
for me.
It's actually Yeah, it's quite good. The
showyu and also the furikake
>> showyu.
>> I think there's like in the furikake
too, but
>> like immediately it's like this really
nice flavor. It's refreshing.
>> It's not eggy.
It's like way better than what I would
normally have at home cuz I would I
would be too lazy to prepare all this
other stuff. M
>> um so yeah, I think it's totally Yeah.
worth coming here. It's a nice treat and
it's kind of fun.
>> So yeah, definitely I think our
reactions are like pretty legitimate.
>> It's really good.
And just for fun, I had my wife and her
sister Ako visit another TKG ery in
Tokyo called Kisaburo, which serves eggs
from various farms across the country.
Unfortunately, on the day of their
visit, Ako's mic didn't work, so we did
a recap online. [music]
Yeah. Yeah. Yeah.
[laughter]
>> [laughter]
>> So
[laughter]
>> So, after hearing Ako's commentary, I
was curious and wanted to hear from our
American and European viewers about
their thoughts on TKG and raw eggs in
general.
>> Sure. I like tamago kakeake gohan. If
it's on the menu, I'll eat it.
>> Yeah, I even love tamago kakeake gohan.
>> Yeah, regularly. I have a [music] quick,
healthy, and like satisfying breakfast.
A lot of protein.
>> I wouldn't go out of my way to get it,
but if somebody made it for me, I would
gladly eat it.
>> I would eat it if it's there, but I
probably wouldn't make it myself.
[music] I think that the raw egg texture
is a little too slimy for me.
>> I have had the TKG for fun. It's It's
okay, but I do not like egg. [laughter]
I made at home. I use a recipe that I
found in a book called Jubilee Cookbook.
Yeah, it was very tasty. [music]
>> I had to kind of get over my fears and
worries a little bit and then it was a
great experience. It tasted very
delicious.
>> I have this very vivid memory from my
childhood where I was speaking cake with
my grandmother in England. I sampled the
cake batter. She reacted as if I had
killed someone and I didn't understand
and she was no no do that. It's very
dangerous. It's you can get salmonella.
>> Most people like my grandfather for
example, they still don't consider
[music] raw egg to be safe
>> cuz I know like egg raw egg is
not what you want to do in America for
sure. Especially want salmonella.
>> They also have this [music] informative
TV shows for kids. From very young age,
we get told the story of the egg being
dangerous.
>> Now, after hearing all this, it made me
wonder, is eating raw eggs actually
dangerous? So, who better to ask than a
food microbiologist. Meet Dr. Andrea
Udder, an associate professor at the
University of Vermont, who researches
salmonella and teaches about global food
safety.
>> The primary type of salmonella people
worry about in eggs is salmonella and
[music] a concern because it gets into
the ovaries and in the ovaries, it's
going to be able to get inside the
[music] eggs. So, washing the outside of
the egg isn't necessarily going to solve
the problem. though it it can be on the
outside of the egg as well because the
chicken anatomy which [music] the
chickens lay eggs then poop through the
same opening. It's a multi-purpose
design. Sanitizing the eggs is going to
help with the outside and you can get
salmonella going from the outside to the
[music] inside, but cleaning the outside
of the eggs as it's required in the US
will solve that issue. And so once you
do that, it removes the protective
bloom, a membrane on the outside of the
egg that would prevent things from
entering from the outside. So then you
have to refrigerate, which is different
from Europe, which doesn't do that
sanitization. So then they can store
their eggs at room temperature. It is
important to note that you still can
have salmonella on the inside and that
would grow really well at room
temperature and not so well at at
refrigeration temperature. But a lot of
home refrigerators don't have
thermometers inside them. And the
refrigerator thermometer that comes with
the refrigerator is only going to test
one part of the refrigerator. So certain
places like the door um could be warmer.
In the US, most farms do vaccinate
against salmonella and
you're still going to miss stuff. And
the question is, do you have safeguards
if you miss something? For the US um
poultry producers are required to buy
from Salmonella and Turidus clean flocks
or to buy their pullets. These are going
to be their future layers. And basically
this is regulated by the National
Poultry Improvement Plan and these are
only for commercial egg layers above
like 3,000 birds. So, in terms of like
actually how well this works, in the
early 2000s, there was an estimate done
by the FDA that one in every 20,000 eggs
had enough salmonella at time of
purchase to make a consumer sex. So,
presumably, it's lower now, but again,
that's going to be commercial. That's
going to be above 3,000 hens.
>> People might assume if it's organic and
if it's small scale, then it's going to
be safer. it it just means that there's
fewer regulations and there's more
unknowns. I [music] don't work
particularly in organic. Um, but I've
done a lot of research on [music]
backyard poultry and depending on the
year. Our first study it was 19%,
[music]
our second study it was 12% of flocks
tested positive [music] for salmonella.
>> Would you ever feel comfortable like in
America like having a raw egg for food?
Yeah, I mean I I actually still eat raw
cookie dough and batter from time to
[music] time. Realistically, if you're
not temperature abusing the eggs, like
leaving them out for long periods of
time, your eggs are relatively fresh.
They're probably not going to give you
salmonola, but there are no guarantees.
I think it was a really big problem. I
think it's less [music] of a problem
now, but cultural biases linger. Raw
oysters are one of the riskiest foods
out there, but people who are raised on
coast love raw oysters. Know what the
risks are and decide if the risks are
worth it to you. If you're in a
high-risisk category for getting really,
really sick, elderly, pregnant,
imunompromised, [music] a small child,
then don't take as many risks. But if
you're young and healthy, yeah, it's
probably reasonable to occasionally take
some risks. There's no such thing as a
risk-free diet. But don't sue me if you
get if you eat raw eggs and get sick.
>> We'll put like a big disclaimer like
disclaimer. Yeah. On top.
>> So, after hearing all of this
information, we wanted to see how
chicken eggs are produced in Japan. And
while we were unfortunately unable to
gain access to a large-scale egg
producer, we were able to visit a
cage-free chicken farm operated by
Bobby's friend Harasan, who you might
remember from our video on Nishiawa
Kura. His business 1010en has won awards
in several startup pitch competitions
over the past year for its innovative
ideas and sustainable business
practices.
>> [screaming]
>> foreign
speech.
Oh no.
Fore!
Foreign! Foreign!
Wow,
have to win. Here
you go.
Fore!
Foreign! Foreign!
Fore
speech.
So once the eggs are washed, they're
separated by weight, packaged, then sent
off, usually reaching customers the next
day. And for those of you who are
curious about egg sizing, here's
Shimoasan to help explain.
>> [laughter]
>> So, I don't want to contradict Harasan,
but according to the small but
well-sighted study done on the
digestibility of proteins in cooked
versus uncooked eggs in humans, around
90% of amino acids in cooked eggs can be
absorbed by the small intestine whereas
only about 50% is absorbed from raw
eggs. So if you're like,
your body might be utilizing more of
those essential amino acids, not just
for repairing your cells, but enzyme and
hormone production and quite a few other
functions in the body. And with that,
let's go back to 1010.
Quiz time. Can you tell which one of
these eggs has a crack in it?
If you guessed A, you'd be correct. And
here's an ASMR bonus for you auditory
tingle heads out there.
But jokes aside, the chicken egg
operation at 1010en is quite impressive.
From the beautiful handcrafted chicken
coops to the sustainable business
practices that Harasan is trying to
spread, it all really makes us
appreciate the work that gets put into
an often undervalued food source. But
let's get back to the question of why is
TKG and raw eggs popular in Japan and
not so much in other countries. Well,
from a risk standpoint, let's look at
the numbers of reported Salmonella cases
in the US, the EU, and Japan from 2023.
I do want to point out that these data
sets were collected by three completely
different governments, and they don't
measure egg specific salmonella cases.
So, take it with a grain of salt. But
the Salmonella numbers in Japan are
strikingly low, even when considering
population differences. But this wasn't
always the case. Salmonella food
poisoning was a problem in Japan like it
was in the United States up until the
late '90s. After which stricter
government regulations helped improve
food safety, namely Salmonella
vaccinations, higher farm hygiene
standards, and clearly labeled
expiration dates on commercial eggs. But
it's not as if Japan's eggs are always
safe to eat raw. Just listen to Harasan.
However, considering what we know about
food safety in Japan and other parts of
the world, I think it's relatively safe
to say that one of the reasons why TKG
and other raw egg dishes are so popular
in Japan is because it's generally safe
to eat them here. But just because
something's safe to eat doesn't mean
it's going to be popular, right? So
perhaps then it's also a question of
food culture. Japanese people, as you
may know, love rice, but not just any
rice. short grain rice. This type of
rice is stickier than medium or long
grain rice. And when you mix it with raw
egg, it creates this nice risoto-like
texture where the egg almost becomes
like a sauce. Now imagine eating raw
eggs with any other popular food staple
like beans, bread, potatoes [music] or
pasta. And I mean just raw egg and a
condiment.
Okay.
>> [laughter]
>> Also in terms of texture, the Japanese
like a lot of neba are slimy foods like
natto, okra, and yamimo. This gooey
texture, which you can see in TKG, might
just conveniently hit the spot for
Japanese people. And finally, Japan's
food culture is known for its raw
protein dishes like fish, chicken,
horse, and beef sashimi. So eating raw
egg probably wasn't so wild to imagine.
Though oddly enough, raw vegetables are
shockingly missing in Japanese diets. So
in conclusion, raw eggs and TKG in
particular might have gotten popular due
to a serendipitous collision of
highquality food hygiene practices, a
large domestic demand and supply of
eggs, and having a food culture that
just so happened to pair well with raw
eggs. We learned a lot during the making
of this video, and I hope you did, too.
We'd like to give a big shout out to
Harasan and everyone at Tenten, our
friend Rosie, the staff at Urinan, Dr.
Utter, our American friends, and of
course, Yanushka, Liam, and Matier.
Thanks for watching. See you next time.
Peace. What are raw eggs like where
you're [music] from?
>> [music]